We’ve updated our Privacy Policy, effective 30 September 2021. You can view the prior Privacy Policy [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#prior-version).

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective: 30 September 2021

Snap Inc. is a camera company. Our products and services – including Snapchat, Bitmoji, Spectacles, advertising and others that link to this Privacy Policy – provide fast and fun ways to express yourself, live in the moment, learn about the world and have fun together!

When you use these services, you’ll share some information with us. So we want to be upfront about the information we collect, how we use it, whom we share it with and the controls we give you to access, update and delete your information.

That’s why we’ve written this Privacy Policy. It’s also why we’ve tried to write it in a way that’s blissfully free of the legalese that often clouds these documents. Of course, if you still have questions about anything in our Privacy Policy, just [contact us](https://support.snapchat.com/).

You should read our entire Privacy Policy, but when you only have a few minutes or want to remember something later on, you can always take a look at [this summary](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/your-privacy/) – so you can review some of the basics in just a few minutes.

Information we collect
----------------------

There are 3 basic categories of information we collect:

*   **Information you provide.**
    
*   **Information we get when you use our services.**
    
*   **Information we get from third parties.**

Here’s a little more detail on each of these categories.

### Information you provide

When you interact with our services, we collect information that you provide to us. For example, most of our services require you to set up a Snapchat account, so we need to collect a few important details about you, such as your name, username, password, email address, phone number and date of birth. We may also ask you to provide us with some additional information that will be publicly visible on our services, such as a profile picture or Bitmoji avatar. Other services, such as commerce products, may require you to provide us with a debit or credit card number and its associated account information.

Of course, you’ll also provide us whatever information you send through our services, such as Snaps and Chats. Keep in mind that the users who view your Snaps, Chats and any other content can always save that content or copy it outside the app. So, the same common sense that applies to the internet at large applies to Snapchat as well: don’t send messages or share content that you wouldn’t want someone to save or share.

When you contact customer support or communicate with us in any other way, we’ll collect whatever information you volunteer or that we need to resolve your question.

### Information we get when you use our services

When you use our services, we collect information about which of those services you’ve used and how you’ve used them. We might know, for instance, that you watched a particular Story, saw a specific advert for a certain period of time and sent a few Snaps. Here’s a fuller explanation of the types of information we collect when you use our services:

*   **Usage information.** We collect information about your activity through our services. For example, we may collect information about:
    
    *   How you interact with our services, such as which Filters you view or apply to Snaps, which Stories you watch on Discover, whether you’re using Spectacles or which search queries you submit.
        
    *   How you communicate with other Snapchatters, such as their names, the time and date of your communications, the number of messages you exchange with your friends, which friends you exchange messages with the most, and your interactions with messages (such as when you open a message or capture a screenshot).
        
*   **Content information.** We collect content you create on our services, such as custom stickers, and information about the content you create or provide, such as if the recipient has viewed the content and the metadata that is provided with the content.
    
*   **Device information.** We collect information from and about the devices you use. For example, we collect:
    
    *   Information about your hardware and software, such as the hardware model, operating system version, device memory, advertising identifiers, unique application identifiers, apps installed, unique device identifiers, browser type, keyboards installed, language, battery level and time zone.
        
    *   Information from device sensors, such as accelerometers, gyroscopes, compasses, microphones and headphone connection.
        
    *   Information about your wireless and mobile network connections, such as mobile phone number, service provider, IP address and signal strength.
        
*   **Device phone book.** Because Snapchat is all about communicating with friends, we may, with your permission, collect information from your device’s phone book.
    
*   **Camera and photos.** Many of our services require us to collect images and other information from your device’s camera and photos. For example, you won’t be able to send Snaps or upload photos from your camera roll unless we can access your camera or photos.
    
*   **Location information.** When you use our services, we may collect information about your location. With your permission, we may also collect information about your precise location using methods that include GPS, wireless networks, mobile towers, Wi-Fi access points and other sensors, such as gyroscopes, accelerometers and compasses.
    
*   **Information collected by cookies and other technologies.** Like most online services and mobile applications, we may use cookies and other technologies such as web beacons, web storage and unique advertising identifiers to collect information about your activity, browser and device. We may also use these technologies to collect information when you interact with services we offer through one of our partners, such as advertising and commerce features. For example, we may use information collected on other websites to show you more relevant adverts. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually remove or reject browser cookies through the settings on your browser or device. Keep in mind though, that removing or rejecting cookies could affect the availability and functionality of our services. To learn more about how we and our partners use cookies on our services and your choices, please check out our [Cookie Policy](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/cookie-policy/).
    
*   **Log information.** We also collect log information when you use our website, such as:
    
    *   Details about how you’ve used our services.
        
    *   Device information, such as your web browser type and language.
        
    *   Access times.
        
    *   Pages viewed.
        
    *   IP address.
        
    *   Identifiers associated with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your device or browser.
        
    *   Pages you visit before or after navigating to our website

### Information we collect from third parties

We may collect information about you from other users, our [affiliates](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snap-affiliates) and third parties. Here are a few examples:

*   If you link your Snapchat account to another service (like Bitmoji or a third-party app), we may receive information from the other service, like how you use that service.
    
*   Advertisers, app developers, publishers and other third parties may share information with us as well. We may use this information, among other ways, to help target or measure the performance of adverts. You can learn more about our use of this kind of third-party data in our [Support Centre](https://support.snapchat.com/a/advertising-preferences).
    
*   If another user uploads their contact list, we may combine information from that user’s contact list with other information we have collected about you.

How we use information
----------------------

What do we do with the information we collect? For the detailed answer, please go [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/your-information). The short answer is: provide you with an amazing set of products and services that we improve relentlessly. Here are the ways we do that:

*   Develop, operate, improve, deliver, maintain and protect our products and services.
    
*   Send you communications, including by email. For example, we may use email to respond to support enquiries or to share information about our products, services and promotional offers that we think may interest you.
    
*   Monitor and analyse trends and usage.
    
*   [Personalise our services](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-by-product#personalization) by, among other things, suggesting friends, profile information or Bitmoji stickers, helping Snapchatters find each other in Snapchat, affiliate and third-party apps and services or customising the content we show you, including adverts.
    
*   Contextualise your experience by, among other things, tagging your Memories content using your precise location information (if, of course, you’ve given us permission to collect that information) and applying other labels based on the content.
    
*   Provide and improve our advertising services, advert targeting and advert measurement, including through the use of your precise location information (again, if you’ve given us permission to collect that information), both on and off our services. See the [“Control over your information”](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#control-over-your-information) section below for more information about Snap Inc.’s advertising practices and your choices.
    
*   Enhance the safety and security of our products and services.
    
*   Verify your identity and prevent fraud or other unauthorised or illegal activity.
    
*   Use information we’ve collected from cookies and other technology to enhance our services and your experience with them.
    
*   Enforce, investigate and report conduct violating our Terms of Service and other usage policies, respond to requests from law enforcement and comply with legal requirements.

We may also use information from Apple’s TrueDepth camera to improve the quality of Lenses. Information from the TrueDepth camera is used in real time – we don’t store this information on our servers or share it with third parties.

How we share information
------------------------

We may share information about you in the following ways:

*   **With other Snapchatters.** We may share the following information with other Snapchatters:
    
    *   Information about you, such as your username, name and Bitmoji.
        
    *   Information about how you have interacted with our services, such as your Snapchat “score”, the names of Snapchatters you are friends with and other information that will help Snapchatters understand your connections with others using our services. For example, because it may not be clear whether a new friend request comes from someone you actually know, we may share whether you and the requester have Snapchat friends in common.
        
    *   Any additional information you have directed us to share. For example, Snap will share your information when you connect your Snapchat account to a third-party app and if you share information or content from Snapchat to the third-party app.
        
    *   Content you post or send. How widely your content is shared depends on your personal settings and the type of service you are using. For example, a Snap may be sent to just a single friend you select, but your My Story content may be seen by any Snapchatter whom you allow to see your My Story.
        
*   **With all Snapchatters, our business partners and the general public.** We may share the following information with all Snapchatters, as well as with our business partners and the general public:
    
    *   Public information like your name, username, profile pictures, Snapcode and Public Profile.
        
    *   Public Content like your Highlights, Custom Stickers, Lenses, Story submissions that are set to be viewable by Everyone and any content that you submit to an inherently public service, like Spotlight, Snap Map and other crowd-sourced services. This content may be viewed, used and shared by the public at large both on and off our services, including through search results, on websites, in apps and in online and offline broadcasts.
        
*   **With our affiliates.** We may share information with entities within the [Snap Inc. family of companies](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snap-affiliates).
    
*   **With third parties.** We may share information about you with service providers who perform services on our behalf, including to measure and optimise the performance of adverts and deliver more relevant adverts, including on third-party websites and apps. Learn more here.
    
    *   We may share information about you with business partners that provide services and functionality on our services. For more information about information collected by third parties on our services, please visit our [Support Site](https://support.snapchat.com/article/integrated-features).
        
    *   We may share information about you, such as device and usage information, to help us and others prevent fraud.
        
    *   We may share information about you for legal, safety and security reasons. We may share information about you if we reasonably believe that disclosing the information is needed to:
        
        *   Comply with any valid legal processing, governmental request or applicable law, rule or regulation.
            
        *   Investigate, remedy, or enforce potential Terms of Service and Community Guidelines violations.
            
        *   Protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our users or others.
            
        *   Detect and resolve any fraud or security concerns.
            
    *   We may share information about you as part of a merger or acquisition. If Snap Inc. gets involved in a merger, asset sale, financing, liquidation or bankruptcy or acquisition of all or some portion of our business to another company, we may share your information with that company before and after the transaction closes. Non-personal information. We may also share with third parties that provide services to us or perform business purposes for us aggregated, non-personally identifiable or de-identified information.
        
*   **Non-personal information.** We may also share with third parties that provide services to us or perform business purposes for us aggregated, non-personally identifiable or de-identified information.

Third-party content and integrations
------------------------------------

Our services may contain third-party content and integrations. Examples include third-party integrations in the Camera, third-party games in Chat and third-party Snap Kit integrations. Through these integrations, you may be providing information to the third party as well as to Snap. We are not responsible for how those third parties collect or use your information. As always, we encourage you to review the privacy policies of every third-party service that you visit or use, including those third parties you interact with through our services. You can learn more about third-party services in Snapchat [here](https://support.snapchat.com/article/integrated-features).

How long we keep your information
---------------------------------

Snapchat lets you capture what it’s like to live in the moment. On our end, that means most messages – like Snaps and Chats – sent in Snapchat will be automatically deleted by default from our servers after we detect they’ve been opened by all recipients or have expired. Other content, like Story posts, are stored for longer. For detailed information about how long we store different types of content, please check out our [Support Site](https://support.snapchat.com/article/when-are-snaps-chats-deleted).

We store other information for longer periods of time. For example:

*   We store your basic account information – such as your name, phone number and email address – and list of friends until you ask us to delete them.
    
*   We store location information for different lengths of time based on how precise it is and which services you use. If location information is associated with a Snap – like those saved to Memories or posted to Snap Map – we’ll retain that location as long as we store the Snap. Pro tip: you can see the location data we retain about you by [downloading your data](https://accounts.snapchat.com/accounts/downloadmydata).

If you ever decide to stop using Snapchat, you can just [ask us to delete your account](https://support.snapchat.com/a/delete-my-account1). We’ll also delete most of the information we’ve collected about you after you’ve been inactive for a while!

Keep in mind that, while our systems are designed to carry out our deletion practices automatically, we cannot promise that deletion will occur within a specific time frame. There may be legal requirements to store your data, and we may need to suspend those deletion practices if we receive valid legal process asking us to preserve content, if we receive reports of abuse or other Terms of Service violations or if your account or content created by you is flagged by others or our systems for abuse or other Terms of Service violations. Finally, we may also retain certain information in backup for a limited period of time or as required by law.

Control over your information
-----------------------------

We want you to be in control of your information, so we provide you with the following tools.

*   **Access, correction and portability. Y**ou can access and edit most of your basic account information right in our apps. You can also use [Download My Data](https://accounts.snapchat.com/accounts/downloadmydata) to obtain a copy of information that isn’t available in our apps in a portable format, so you can move it or store it wherever you like. Because your privacy is important to us, we will ask you to verify your identity or provide additional information before we let you access or update your personal information. We may also reject your request to access or update your personal information for a number of reasons, including, for example, if the request risks the privacy of other users or is unlawful.
    
*   **Revoking permissions.** In most cases, if you let us use your information, you can simply revoke your permission by changing the settings in the app or on your device if your device offers those options. Of course, certain services may lose full functionality if you do that.
    
*   **Deletion.** While we hope you’ll remain a lifelong Snapchatter, if for some reason you ever want to delete your account, just go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/delete-my-account1) to learn how. You can also delete some information in the app, like photos you’ve saved to Memories, Spotlight submissions and search history.
    
*   **Advertising preferences.** We try to show you adverts that we think will be relevant to your interests. If you would like to modify the information we and our advertising partners use to select these ads, you can do so in the app and through your device preferences. Please go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/advertising-preferences) to learn more.
    
*   **Communicating with other Snapchatters.** It’s important to us that you stay in control over whom you communicate with. That’s why we’ve built a number of tools in Settings that let you indicate, among other things, who you want to see your Stories, whether you’d like to receive Snaps from just your friends or all Snapchatters and whether you’d like to block another Snapchatter from contacting you again. Please go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/article/privacy-settings2) to learn more.

International data transfers
----------------------------

We may collect your personal information from, transfer it to and store and process it in the United States and other countries outside of where you live. Whenever we share information outside of where you live, when we are legally required to do so, we make sure an adequate transfer mechanism is in place. We also make sure any third parties we share information with have an adequate transfer mechanism in place, as well. You can find more information on what data transfer mechanism we use [here](https://businesshelp.snapchat.com/s/article/snap-privacy-faq) and the categories of third parties we share information with [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snapchat-service-providers).

State and region specific information
-------------------------------------

You may have specific privacy rights in your state or region. For example, in the United States, residents of California and other states have specific privacy rights. Snapchatters in the European Economic Area (EEA), the UK, Brazil, the Republic of Korea and other jurisdictions also have specific rights. We keep an up-to-date overview of state and region specific disclosures [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/state-region-information).

Children
--------

Our services are not intended for – and we don’t direct them to – anyone under 13. And that’s why we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13. In addition, we may limit how we collect, use and store some of the information of EEA and UK users between 13 and 16. In some cases, this means we will be unable to provide certain functionality to these users. If we need to rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your information and your country requires consent from a parent, we may require your parent’s consent before we collect and use that information.

Revisions to the Privacy Policy
-------------------------------

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. But when we do, we’ll let you know one way or another. Sometimes, we’ll let you know by revising the date at the top of the Privacy Policy that’s available on our website and mobile application. Other times, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our websites’ home pages or providing you with an in-app notification).

* * *

We’ve updated our Privacy Policy, effective 30 September 2021. You can view the prior Privacy Policy [](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#prior-version)below.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* * *

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective: 9 July 2021

Snap Inc. is a camera company. Our products and services – including Snapchat, Bitmoji, Spectacles, advertising and others that link to this Privacy Policy – provide fast and fun ways to express yourself, live in the moment, learn about the world and have fun together!

When you use these services, you’ll share some information with us. So we want to be upfront about the information we collect, how we use it, whom we share it with and the controls we give you to access, update and delete your information.

That’s why we’ve written this Privacy Policy. It’s also why we’ve tried to write it in a way that’s blissfully free of the legalese that often clouds these documents. Of course, if you still have questions about anything in our Privacy Policy, just [contact us](https://support.snapchat.com/).

You should read our entire Privacy Policy, but when you only have a few minutes or want to remember something later on, you can always take a look at [this summary](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/your-privacy/) – so you can review some of the basics in just a few minutes.

Information we collect
----------------------

There are 3 basic categories of information we collect:

*   **Information you provide.**
    
*   **Information we get when you use our services.**
    
*   **Information we get from third parties.**

Here’s a little more detail on each of these categories.

### Information you provide

When you interact with our services, we collect information that you provide to us. For example, most of our services require you to set up a Snapchat account, so we need to collect a few important details about you, such as your name, username, password, email address, phone number and date of birth. We may also ask you to provide us with some additional information that will be publicly visible on our services, such as a profile picture or Bitmoji avatar. Other services, such as commerce products, may require you to provide us with a debit or credit card number and its associated account information.

Of course, you’ll also provide us whatever information you send through our services, such as Snaps and Chats. Keep in mind that the users who view your Snaps, Chats and any other content can always save that content or copy it outside the app. So, the same common sense that applies to the internet at large applies to Snapchat as well: don’t send messages or share content that you wouldn’t want someone to save or share.

When you contact customer support or communicate with us in any other way, we’ll collect whatever information you volunteer or that we need to resolve your question.

### Information we get when you use our services

When you use our services, we collect information about which of those services you’ve used and how you’ve used them. We might know, for instance, that you watched a particular Story, saw a specific advert for a certain period of time and sent a few Snaps. Here’s a fuller explanation of the types of information we collect when you use our services:

*   **Usage information.** We collect information about your activity through our services. For example, we may collect information about:
    
    *   How you interact with our services, such as which Filters you view or apply to Snaps, which Stories you watch on Discover, whether you’re using Spectacles or which search queries you submit.
        
    *   How you communicate with other Snapchatters, such as their names, the time and date of your communications, the number of messages you exchange with your friends, which friends you exchange messages with the most and your interactions with messages (such as when you open a message or capture a screenshot).
        
*   **Content information.** We collect content you create on our services, such as custom stickers, and information about the content you create or provide, such as if the recipient has viewed the content and the metadata that is provided with the content.
    
*   **Device information.** We collect information from and about the devices you use. For example, we collect:
    
    *   Information about your hardware and software, such as the hardware model, operating system version, device memory, advertising identifiers, unique application identifiers, apps installed, unique device identifiers, browser type, language, battery level and time zone.
        
    *   Information from device sensors, such as accelerometers, gyroscopes, compasses, microphones and headphone connection.
        
    *   Information about your wireless and mobile network connections, such as mobile phone number, service provider, IP address and signal strength.
        
*   **Device phone book.** Because Snapchat is all about communicating with friends, we may, with your permission, collect information from your device’s phone book.
    
*   **Camera and photos.** Many of our services require us to collect images and other information from your device’s camera and photos. For example, you won’t be able to send Snaps or upload photos from your camera roll unless we can access your camera or photos.
    
*   **Location information.** When you use our services, we may collect information about your location. With your permission, we may also collect information about your precise location using methods that include GPS, wireless networks, mobile towers, Wi-Fi access points and other sensors, such as gyroscopes, accelerometers and compasses.
    
*   **Information collected by cookies and other technologies.** Like most online services and mobile applications, we may use cookies and other technologies such as web beacons, web storage and unique advertising identifiers to collect information about your activity, browser and device. We may also use these technologies to collect information when you interact with services we offer through one of our partners, such as advertising and commerce features. For example, we may use information collected on other websites to show you more relevant adverts. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually remove or reject browser cookies through the settings on your browser or device. Keep in mind though, that removing or rejecting cookies could affect the availability and functionality of our services. To learn more about how we and our partners use cookies on our services and your choices, please check out our [Cookie Policy](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/cookie-policy/).
    
*   **Log information.** We also collect log information when you use our website, such as:
    
    *   Details about how you’ve used our services.
        
    *   Device information, such as your web browser type and language.
        
    *   Access times.
        
    *   Pages viewed.
        
    *   IP address.
        
    *   Identifiers associated with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your device or browser.
        
    *   Pages you visit before or after navigating to our website.

### Information we collect from third parties

We may collect information about you from other users, our [affiliates](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snap-affiliates) and third parties. Here are a few examples:

*   If you link your Snapchat account to another service (like Bitmoji or a third-party app), we may receive information from the other service, like how you use that service.
    
*   Advertisers, app developers, publishers and other third parties may share information with us as well. We may use this information, among other ways, to help target or measure the performance of adverts. You can learn more about our use of this kind of third-party data in our [Support Centre](https://support.snapchat.com/a/advertising-preferences).
    
*   If another user uploads their contact list, we may combine information from that user’s contact list with other information we have collected about you.

How we use information
----------------------

What do we do with the information we collect? For the detailed answer, please go [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/your-information). The short answer is: provide you with an amazing set of products and services that we improve relentlessly. Here are the ways we do that:

*   Develop, operate, improve, deliver, maintain and protect our products and services.
    
*   Send you communications, including by email. For example, we may use email to respond to support enquiries or to share information about our products, services and promotional offers that we think may interest you.
    
*   Monitor and analyse trends and usage.
    
*   [Personalise our services](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-by-product#personalization) by, among other things, suggesting friends, profile information or Bitmoji stickers or customising the content we show you, including adverts.
    
*   Contextualise your experience by, among other things, tagging your Memories content using your precise location information (if, of course, you’ve given us permission to collect that information) and applying other labels based on the content.
    
*   Provide and improve our advertising services, advert targeting and advert measurement, including through the use of your precise location information (again, if you’ve given us permission to collect that information), both on and off our services. See the [Control over your information](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#control-over-your-information) section below for more information about Snap Inc.’s advertising practices and your choices.
    
*   Enhance the safety and security of our products and services.
    
*   Verify your identity and prevent fraud or other unauthorised or illegal activity.
    
*   Use information we’ve collected from cookies and other technology to enhance our services and your experience with them.
    
*   Enforce our Terms of Service and other usage policies and comply with legal requirements.

We may also use information from Apple’s TrueDepth camera to improve the quality of Lenses. Information from the TrueDepth camera is used in real time – we don’t store this information on our servers or share it with third parties.

How we share information
------------------------

We may share information about you in the following ways:

*   **With other Snapchatters.** We may share the following information with other Snapchatters:
    
    *   Information about you, such as your username, name and Bitmoji.
        
    *   Information about how you have interacted with our services, such as your Snapchat “score”, the names of Snapchatters you are friends with and other information that will help Snapchatters understand your connections with others using our services. For example, because it may not be clear whether a new friend request comes from someone you actually know, we may share whether you and the requester have Snapchat friends in common.
        
    *   Any additional information you have directed us to share. For example, Snap will share your information when you connect your Snapchat account to a third-party app and if you share information or content from Snapchat to the third-party app.
        
    *   Content you post or send. How widely your content is shared depends on your personal settings and the type of service you are using. For example, a Snap may be sent to just a single friend you select, but your My Story content may be seen by any Snapchatter whom you allow to see your My Story.
        
*   **With all Snapchatters, our business partners and the general public.** We may share the following information with all Snapchatters, as well as with our business partners and the general public:
    
    *   Public information such as your name, username, Snapcode and profile pictures.
        
    *   Story submissions that are set to be viewable by Everyone and any content that you submit to an inherently public service, like Our Story and other crowd-sourced services. This content may be viewed and shared by the public at large both on and off our services, including through search results, on websites, in apps and in online and offline broadcasts.
        
*   **With our affiliates.** We may share information with entities within the [Snap Inc. family of companies](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snap-affiliates).
    
*   **With third parties.** We may share information about you with service providers who perform services on our behalf, including to measure and optimise the performance of adverts and deliver more relevant adverts, including on third-party websites and apps. Learn more [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snapchat-service-providers).
    
    *   We may share information about you with business partners that provide services and functionality on our services. For more information about information collected by third parties on our services, please visit our [Support Site](https://support.snapchat.com/article/integrated-features).
        
    *   We may share information about you, such as device and usage information, to help us and others prevent fraud.
        
    *   We may share information about you for legal, safety and security reasons. We may share information about you if we reasonably believe that disclosing the information is needed to:
        
        *   Comply with any valid legal processing, governmental request or applicable law, rule or regulation.
            
        *   Investigate, remedy or enforce potential Terms of Service violations.
            
        *   Protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our users or others.
            
        *   Detect and resolve any fraud or security concerns.
            
    *   We may share information about you as part of a merger or acquisition. If Snap Inc. gets involved in a merger, asset sale, financing, liquidation or bankruptcy or acquisition of all or some portion of our business to another company, we may share your information with that company before and after the transaction closes.

We may also share with third parties that provide services to us or perform business purposes for us aggregated, non-personally identifiable or de-identified information.

Third-party content and integrations
------------------------------------

Our services may contain third-party content and integrations. Examples include third-party integrations in camera search, third-party games in Chat and third-party Snap Kit integrations. Through these integrations, you may be providing information to the third party as well as to Snap. We are not responsible for how those third parties collect or use your information. As always, we encourage you to review the privacy policies of every third-party service that you visit or use, including those third parties you interact with through our services. You can learn more about third-party services in Snapchat [here](https://support.snapchat.com/article/integrated-features).

How long we keep your information
---------------------------------

Snapchat lets you capture what it’s like to live in the moment. On our end, that means most messages – like Snaps and Chats – sent in Snapchat will be automatically deleted by default from our servers after we detect they’ve been opened by all recipients or have expired. Other content, like Story posts, are stored for longer. For detailed information about how long we store different types of content, please check out our [Support Site](https://support.snapchat.com/article/when-are-snaps-chats-deleted).

We store other information for longer periods of time. For example:

*   We store your basic account information – such as your name, phone number and email address – and list of friends until you ask us to delete them.
    
*   We store location information for different lengths of time based on how precise it is and which services you use. For example, if you use the Map, we store information about your favorite places for up to 40 days so we can personalise and improve your experience. If location information is associated with a Snap – like those saved to Memories or posted to Our Story – we’ll retain that location as long as we store the Snap.
    
*   We’re constantly collecting and updating information about the things you might like and dislike, so we can provide you with more relevant content and advertisements. Please go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/advertising-preferences) to learn more.

If you ever decide to stop using Snapchat, you can just [ask us to delete your account](https://support.snapchat.com/a/delete-my-account1). We’ll also delete most of the information we’ve collected about you after you’ve been inactive for a while – but don’t worry, we’ll try to contact you first!

Keep in mind that, while our systems are designed to carry out our deletion practices automatically, we cannot promise that deletion will occur within a specific time frame. There may be legal requirements to store your data, and we may need to suspend those deletion practices if we receive valid legal process asking us to preserve content, if we receive reports of abuse or other Terms of Service violations or if your account or content created by you is flagged by our automated systems for abuse or other Terms of Service violations. Finally, we may also retain certain information in backup for a limited period of time or as required by law.

Control over your information
-----------------------------

We want you to be in control of your information, so we provide you with the following tools.

*   **Access, correction and portability. Y**ou can access and edit most of your basic account information right in our apps. You can also use [Download My Data](https://accounts.snapchat.com/accounts/downloadmydata) to obtain a copy of information that isn’t available in our apps in a portable format, so you can move it or store it wherever you like. Because your privacy is important to us, we will ask you to verify your identity or provide additional information before we let you access or update your personal information. We may also reject your request to access or update your personal information for a number of reasons, including, for example, if the request risks the privacy of other users or is unlawful.
    
*   **Revoking permissions.** In most cases, if you let us use your information, you can simply revoke your permission by changing the settings in the app or on your device if your device offers those options. Of course, certain services may lose full functionality if you do that.
    
*   **Deletion.** While we hope you’ll remain a lifelong Snapchatter, if for some reason you ever want to delete your account, just go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/delete-my-account1) to learn how. You can also delete some information in the app, like photos you’ve saved to Memories, Our Story submissions and search history.
    
*   **Advertising preferences.** We try to show you adverts that we think will be relevant to your interests. If you would like to modify the information we and our advertising partners use to select these ads, you can do so in the app and through your device preferences. Please go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/advertising-preferences) to learn more.
    
*   **Communicating with other Snapchatters.** It’s important to us that you stay in control over whom you communicate with. That’s why we’ve built a number of tools in Settings that let you indicate, among other things, who you want to see your Stories, whether you’d like to receive Snaps from just your friends or all Snapchatters and whether you’d like to block another Snapchatter from contacting you again. Please go [here](https://support.snapchat.com/article/privacy-settings2) to learn more.

Users in the European Union
---------------------------

If you’re a user in the European Union, you should know that Snap Inc. is the controller of your personal information. Here is some additional information we would like to bring to your attention:

### Rights of access, deletion, correction and portability

You can exercise your rights of access, deletion, correction and portability as described in the C[ontrol Over Your Information](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#control-over-your-information) section above.

### Bases for using your information

Your country only allows us to use your personal information when certain conditions apply. These conditions are called “legal bases” and, at Snap, we typically rely on one of four:

*   **Contract.** One reason we might use your information is that you’ve entered into an agreement with us. For example, when you buy an On-Demand Filter and accept our Custom Creative Tools Terms, we need to use some of your information to collect payment and make sure we show your Filter to the right people at the right place and time.
    
*   **Legitimate interest.** Another reason we might use your information is that we have – or a third party has – a legitimate interest in doing so. For example, we need to use your information to provide and improve our services, including protecting your account, delivering your Snaps, providing customer support and helping you find friends and content we think you’ll like. Because most of our services are free, we also use some information about you to try to show you adverts you’ll find interesting. An important point to understand about legitimate interest is that our interests don’t outweigh your right to privacy, so we only rely on legitimate interest when we think the way we are using your data doesn’t significantly impact your privacy or would be expected by you or there is a compelling reason to do so. We explain our legitimate business reasons for using your information in more detail [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/your-information).
    
*   **Consent.** In some cases we’ll ask for consent to use your information for specific purposes. If we do, we’ll make sure you can revoke your consent in our services or through your device permissions. Even if we’re not relying on consent to use your information, we may ask you for permission to access data like contacts and location.
    
*   **Legal obligation.** We may be required to use your personal information to comply with the law, such as when we respond to valid legal processing or need to take action to protect our users. Our policy is to notify Snapchatters when we receive legal process seeking their account information, with some exceptions. Learn more [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/transparency/).

### Your right to object

You have the right to object to our use of your information. With many types of data, we’ve provided you with the ability to simply delete it if you don’t want us processing it any more. For other types of data, we’ve given you the ability to stop the use of your data by disabling the feature altogether. You can do these things in the app. If there are other types of information you don’t agree with us processing, you can [contact us](https://support.snapchat.com/).

### International transfers

We may collect your personal information from, transfer it to and store and process it in the United States and other countries outside of where you live. Whenever we share information of EU users outside the EU, we make sure an adequate transfer mechanism is in place. You can find more information on the categories of third parties we share information with [here](https://support.snapchat.com/a/snapchat-service-providers).

**EU representative**

Snap Inc. has appointed Snap B.V. as its EU representative. You can contact the EU representative [here](https://support.snapchat.com/i-need-help?start=5749439348080640) or at:

Snap B.V. Keizersgracht 440 B, 1016 GD Amsterdam, The Netherlands

**Complaints or questions?** If you’re based in the EU, you can always file a complaint with the [supervisory authority](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en) in your Member State. Additionally, we have appointed a Data Protection Officer (“DPO”). To contact our DPO, please email dpo @ snap.com.

Users in Brazil
---------------

If you’re a user in Brazil, you should know that Snap Inc. is the controller of your personal information. Here is some additional information we would like to bring to your attention:

Rights of access, deletion, correction and portability
------------------------------------------------------

You can exercise your rights of access, deletion, correction and portability as described in the “[Control over your information](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#control-over-your-information)” section of the Privacy Policy.

Bases for using your information
--------------------------------

Your country only allows us to use your personal information when certain conditions apply. These conditions are called “legal bases” and, at Snap, we typically rely on one of four:

*   **Contract.** One reason we might use your information is because you’ve entered into an agreement with us. For example, when you buy an On-Demand Geofilter and accept our Custom Creative Tools Terms, we need to use some of your information to collect payment and make sure we show your Geofilter to the right people at the right place and time.
    
*   **Legitimate interest.** Another reason we might use your information is because we have—or a third party has—a legitimate interest in doing so. For instance, we need to use your information to provide and improve our services, including protecting your account, delivering your Snaps, providing customer support, and helping you find friends and content we think you’ll like. As most of our services are free, we also use some information about you to try and show you ads you’ll find interesting. An important point to understand about legitimate interest is that our interests don’t outweigh your right to privacy, so we only rely on legitimate interest when we think the way we are using your data doesn’t significantly impact your privacy or would be expected by you, or there is a compelling reason to do so. We explain our legitimate business reasons for using your information in more detail [here](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/your-information).
    
*   **Consent.** In some cases we’ll ask for consent to use your information for specific purposes. If we do, we’ll make sure you can revoke your consent in our services or through your device permissions. Even if we’re not relying on consent to use your information, we may ask you for permission to access data like contacts and location.
    
*   **Legal obligation.** We may be required to use your personal information to comply with the law, like when we respond to valid legal process or need to take action to protect our users.

**Your right to object**

You have the right to object to our use of your information. With many types of data, we’ve provided you with the ability to simply delete it if you don’t want us processing it any more. For other types of data, we’ve given you the ability to stop the use of your data by disabling the feature altogether. You can do these things in the app. If there are other types of information you don’t agree with us processing, you can contact us.

**Complaints or questions?**  You can always file a complaint with the national authority in your country. Additionally, we have appointed a Data Protection Officer (“DPO”). To contact our DPO, please email dpo @ snap.com.

Users in Mexico
---------------

If you’re a user in Mexico, you should know that Snap Inc., located at 2772 Donald Douglas Loop North, Santa Monica, California 90405, is the controller of your personal information. Here is some additional information we would like to bring to your attention:

Rights of access, rectification and cancellation
------------------------------------------------

You can exercise your rights of access, rectification and cancellation as described in the “[Control over your information](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/privacy-policy#control-over-your-information)” section of the Privacy Policy.

Your right to object or challenge
---------------------------------

You have the right to object to or challenge our use of your information. With many types of data, we’ve provided you with the ability to simply delete it if you don’t want us processing it any more. For other types of data, we’ve given you the ability to stop the use of your data by disabling the feature altogether. You can do these things in the app. If there are other types of information you don’t agree with our processing, you can [contact us](https://support.snapchat.com/).

California residents
--------------------

If you’re a California resident, you have certain privacy rights under California law, including the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”). Our California Privacy Notice specifies these rights. [Check it out](https://www.snap.com/en-GB/privacy/california-privacy-notice).

Children
--------

Our services are not intended for – and we don’t direct them to – anyone under 13. And that’s why we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13. In addition, we may limit how we collect, use and store some of the information of EU users between 13 and 16. In some cases, this means we will be unable to provide certain functionality to these users. If we need to rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your information and your country requires consent from a parent, we may require your parent’s consent before we collect and use that information.

Revisions to the Privacy Policy
-------------------------------

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. But when we do, we’ll let you know one way or another. Sometimes, we’ll let you know by revising the date at the top of the Privacy Policy that’s available on our website and mobile application. Other times, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our websites’ home pages or providing you with an in-app notification).
